# Mina Abdo

**Phone**: (+20) 1280325553

Email address: mina.abdo2030@gmail.com

• Address: New Maadi, Cairo, Egypt.

## **Professional summary**

Software Engineering Specialist Web Developer with 8+ years' experience specializing in back end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including ASP.Net (Web-forms, MVC), Angular, JavaScript, CSS, MS SQL. Committed team player with a track record of delivering high-quality solutions under pressure, dedicated to driving excellence and innovation in software development.

# **Professional experience**

## Software Engineering Specialist, Link Development, Cairo, Egypt

January 2024 – on going

- Developing new features using SQL, Angular 8, MVC, Umbraco.
- Debugging software, identified root causes, and proposed solutions to software issues.
- Reviewing software requirements and providing feedback to ensure that the software meets customer needs
- stablished a set of best practices and documented procedures for software testing, resulting in improved accuracy and reliability of software products.
- Engaging in revamping the website of the SSA (Saudi Space Agency).

#### Senior Software Engineer, Link Development, Cairo, Egypt

January 2021 - January 2024

- Optimized application performance by refactoring code.
- Developed new features using SQL, Angular 8, MVC, Site core, Umbraco.
- Engaged in revamping the website of the SSA (Saudi Space Agency) and revamping the website of Faisal Islamic Bank.

## Software Engineer, Link Development, Cairo, Egypt

#### February 2019 – January 2021

- Developed new features using SharePoint, SQL, AngularJS, MVC, Signal R.
- Implemented new admin panel to reduce data entry time by 50%, optimized existing services, resulting in a 25% performance enhancement and lookup services for the GAFI system (General Authority for Investment & Free Zones).

## Software Development Supervisor, HITS Solutions, Cairo, Egypt

#### January 2017 - January 2019

- Contributed to the development of the (Hits HR and Payroll System), surveillance system, and tracking system.
- Identified and implemented best practices for software development.
- Collaborated on the development of (Hits HR and Payroll System) mobile applications leveraging Xamarin Forms.

- Directed a team of five junior software engineers to successfully develop and deploy a sophisticated application within a tight deadline.
- Provided guidance and mentorship to junior staff and undergraduate interns.
- Developed new features using ASP.NET, SQL.

Junior Software Engineer, HITS Solution, Cairo, Egypt

March 2016 - January 2017

- Innovated new functionalities using ASP.NET, SQL.
- Sustained existing functionalities.
- Contributed to the development of the (Hits HR and Payroll System).
- Reviewed software requirements and provided feedback to ensure that the software meets customer needs.

## **Education**

BACHELOR'S DEGREE OF COMPUTER SCIENCE, [Faculty of Computers and Artificial Intelligence – Cairo University], [Cairo], [Egypt]

September [2011] - June [2015]

## Languages

English (Level B2)

Arabic (Mother tounge)

# **Digital Skills**

ASP.NET (Web-forms, MVC) | .NetCore | SQL Server | Angular | TypeScript | C# | HTML | JavaScript | CSS |

Xamarin Forms | SOLID Design Principles | Design Patterns | CMS (Umbraco, SiteCore) | Share Point | SignalR

# **Soft Skills**

Communication | Problem-Solving | Creativity | Team Player | Self-Motivation | Flexibility and Adaptability | Attention to Detail | Time Management | Responsibility and Accountability | Analytical Mindset

#### Certificates

- Generative AI for Beginners (2024)
   online course Great Learning Academy
- Introduction to ASP.Net Core (2024)
   online course Great Learning Academy
- Angular7 for Beginners (2024)
   online course Great Learning Academy
- Angular7 for Intermediate Level (2024) online course - Great Learning Academy
- Angular7 for Advanced Level (2024) online course - Great Learning Academy
- React JS Tutorial (2024)
   online course Great Learning Academy